Guide to the Werner Pfeiffer Collection, 1953-2017
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Werner Pfeiffer Collection
1953-2017
Pfeiffer, Werner, 1937-
24 cubic feet
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Prints, drawings, paintings, collages, sculptures and artists books created by Pfeiffer, as well as publicity material and other records relating to his art career.
Biographical Note
Werner Pfeiffer was born in 1937 in Stuttgart in the southwestern part of Germany. He studied at the Akademie der Bildenden Künste in his home town. In 1961 he emigrated to the United States. Initially, he was active as a designer and art director on a variety of projects. In this capacity he received many citations and awards from the New York Art Directors Club, the New York Type Directors Club, the New York Society of Illustrators, and the American Institute of Graphic Arts. His design work has been widely published in the international design literature in magazines such as Graphis, Gebrauchsgrafik, Print, Modern Publicity and Art Direction. In 1969 he was appointed Professor of Art at Pratt Institute in New York. At the same time he assumed the position of director of the Pratt Adlib Press, a publishing venture of the Department of Graphic Art at Pratt. In the late 1960s he started to concentrate exclusively on his own work as sculptor, printmaker and painter. He lives in Red Hook, a small community in the mid-Hudson region in New York State.
His books, collages, drawings, prints, paintings and sculptures have been shown internationally in more than 100 group exhibitions and in over 75 solo shows in countries such as Canada, Chile, Colombia, France, Germany, Israel, Sweden, Switzerland and throughout the United States.
Over the years he has received numerous public sculpture commissions from the State of Connecticut, the Federal Government of Germany, the State of Niedersachsen in Germany and the State of Massachusetts. Commissions in the private sector include projects for corporations such as Baxter International, Chemical Bank, Zürich, the Hartford Insurance Group, Lackwerke Wülfling, Daimler-Benz Credit Corp./USA and the Hartford Courant, a part of the Time Mirror Group.
Besides being part of many private collections here and abroad, his work is represented in major museums, and university and public collections throughout the world.
Scope and Content Note
Prints, drawings, paintings, collages, sculptures and artists books created by Pfeiffer, as well as publicity material and other records relating to his art career.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the
Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Carle, Eric; Eichenberg, Fritz, 1901-1990; Gekeler, Hans; Grashow, James, 1942-; Korf, Kumi; Kyle, Hedi; Landau, Jacob, 1917-2001; Ponce de Leon, Michael, 1922-; Saris, Anthony; Uehara, Carole
Organizations:
Pratt Adlib Press
Subjects:
Artists' books--New York (State); Artists--New York (State)
Document Types:
Book objects; Artists' books (books); Drawings (visual works)
VCL Categories
Art and Artists; Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2018.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in multiple accessions, beginning in 2016, as gifts from Werner Pfeiffer.
Series List
- 1000 Miscellaneous
  - 1001: Early School Work
  - 1002: Graphic Design Samples
  - 1003: Teaching Activity
  - 1004: Presentations
  - 1005: X-mas Cards
  - 1006: Special Gifts
- 2000 Drawings
  - 2001: Drawings
  - 2002: Sketchbooks
  - 2003: Scroll Drawings
    There are 90 images, each on a field 8" x 10", drawn on tissue paper between February 7 – February 13, 1978. They were done as a linear study of moving images, with sharp edged, aggressive expressions. The scroll is 78' long. 27 of these images were later used in Errantry, a documentation of all the conflicts and wars of the 20th century.
  - 2004: Doodles
  - 2005: Banana Drawings
- 3000 Prints
  - 3001: Drawings and Sketches of Prints
  - 3002: Early Prints and Woodcuts
  - 3003: Experimental Prints
- 4000 Sculptures
  - 3001: Drawings
- 5000 Paintings
  - 5001: Early Pieces
  - 5002: Shaped and Rotating Canvases
  - 5003: System-Kunst, Assembly Art, Zippers
- 6000 Collages
  - 6001: Collage Constructions
  - 6002: Collages
- 7000 Books
  - 7005: Experimental Pieces
- 8000 Publicity and Records
  - 8001: Visual Diaries
  - 8002: Announcements and Catalogues
  - 8003: Audio-Visual, Exhibits and Awards, Writing
  - 8006: Correspondence and Records
  - 8007: Posters
- 9000 Private Collection Items
  - 9003: Prints
  - 9004: Greeting Cards
  - 9005: Adlib Press
Container List
- 1000 MISCELLANEOUS
  - 1001: Early School Work
    - Gouache Drawing, (19.5 x 21.5) (1001—001)
    - Drawing, (11.5 x 14.5) (1001—002)
    - Figure Drawing, (11.25 x 16.5) (1001—003)
    - Charcoal Drawing, (15.25 x 20.5) (1001—004)
    - Lift-Off Drawing, (18 x 22) (1001—005)
    - Still Life – drawing, (12.5 x 14.5) (1001—006)
    - Perspective Drawing, (7 x 21) (1001—007)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—008)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—009)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—010)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—011)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—012)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—013)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—014)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—015)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—016)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—017)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—018)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—019)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—020)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—021)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—022)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—023)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—024)
    - Travel Sketches – charcoal, (16.5 x 11.75) (1001—025)
    - Pencil Drawing, (11.5 x 15) (1001—026)
    - Pencil Drawing, (11.5 x 13.25) (1001—027)
    - Collage, (11 x 12) (1001—028)
    - Collage, (12 x 16.5) (1001—029)
    - Collage - color design, (14 x 16) (1001—030)
    - Color Study - crayon, (10 x 16) (1001—031)
    - Encaustic, (9.25 x 19.5) (1001—032)
    - Encaustic, (9.25 x 19.5) (1001—033)
    - Lettering – linocut – variant 1, (15.5 x 22) (1001—034)
    - Lettering – linocut – variant 2, (15.5 x 22) (1001—035)
    - Lettering – linocut – variant 3, (15.5 x 22) (1001—036)
    - Writing – linocut – variant 1, (17 x 22) (1001—037)
    - Writing – linocut – variant 2, (17 x 22) (1001—038)
    - Calligraphic Exercise, (17 x 24) (1001—039)
    - Calligraphic Exercise, (15.25 x 22) (1001—040)
    - Lettering Exercise, (12 x 17) (1001—041)
    - Calligraphy – linocut, (17 x 24) (1001—042)
    - Calligraphy – linocut, (17 x 22) (1001—043)
    - Alphabet Design – caps, (17 x 24) (1001—044)
    - Alphabet Design – l.c., (17 x 24) (1001—045)
    - Memorial Design, (8.75 x 15.75) (1001—046)
    - Type Design for Memorial, (19 x 25) (1001—047)
    - Lettering Exercise – litho, (15.25 x 21) (1001—048)
    - Inv. for Student Ball, (5.5 x 27) (1001—049)
    - Lithograph, (17 x 24) (1001—050)
    - Lithograph – Marseille, (17 x 24.5) (1001—051)
    - Lithograph – Gauze Print, (19 x 27) (1001—052)
    - Lithograph – Plant, (20 x 21) (1001—053)
    - Lithograph – small fields, (20 x 20) (1001—054)
    - Trademark, (11 x 15.25) (1001—055)
    - Book Jacket, (6.25 x 8.75) (1001—056)
    - Book Jacket, (6.25 x 8.75) (1001—057)
    - Book Jacket, (6.25 x 8.75) (1001—058)
    - Book Jacket, (6.25 x 8.75) (1001—059)
    - Linocut – variant 1, (11 x 15) (1001—060)
    - Linocut – variant 2, (11 x 15) (1001—061)
    - Linocut – variant 3, (11 x 15) (1001—062)
    - Linocut – variant 4, (11 x 15) (1001—063)
    - Color Study – crayons, (5.25 x 6.25) (1001—064)
    - Color Study – encaustic, (5.25 x 7) (1001—065)
    - Color Study – crayons, (8 x 8.25) (1001—066)
    - Writing – lift-off technique, (10 x 11.25) (1001—067)
    - Aquarell, (8 x 8.5) (1001—068)
    - Aquarell, (15.5 x 11.5) (1001—069)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—070)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—071)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—072)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—073)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—074)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (16.5 x 11.5) (1001—075)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (8.25 x 11.25) (1001—076)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (8.25 x 11.25) (1001—077)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (8.25 x 11.25) (1001—078)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (8.25 x 11.25) (1001—079)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (11 x 15.5) (1001—080)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (22 x 15.5) (1001—081)
    - Typographic Page Layouts, (22 x 15.5) (1001—082)
    - Rilke Book, (8.5 x 10.25) (1001—083)
    - Rilke Book – variant 2, (8.5 x 10.25) (1001—084)
    - Razor Blade Packaging, 15.25 x 22.25) (1001—085)
    - Study for Painting, (2.5 x 5) (1001—086)
    - Study for Painting, (3 x 8) (1001—087)
    - Seasons Greetings Card, (8.5 x 8.5) (1001—088)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—089)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—090)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—091)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—092)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—093)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—094)
    - Record Cover – type only, (7.25 x 7.25) (1001—095)
    - Announcement - linocut, (3 x 7.25) (1001—096)
    - Announcement – linocut, (4 x 8) (1001—097)
    - Seasons Greetings, (5.5 x 12) (1001—098)
    - Announcement – linocut, (4 x 8) (1001—099)
    - Announcement – linocut, (4 x 13.25) (1001—100)
    - Color Sketch for linocut, (4 x 10) (1001—101)
    - First Proof linocut, (4 x 10) (1001—102)
    - Final Proof, (4 x 10) (1001—103)
    - Linocut – plate, (4 x 10) (1001—104)
    - Outline Drawing, (15.5 x 11.5) (1001—105)
    - Watercolor, (15 x 11) (1001—106)
  - 1002: Graphic Design Samples
    - Type Experiments, (8 x 18) (1002—001)
    - Type Experiments, (8 x 17) (1002—002)
    - Numbers, (12 x 14) (1002—003)
    - Type Experiments, (8.25 x 8.75) (1002—004)
    - Type Experiments – USA Series, (7.5 x 7.5) (1002—005)
    - Type Experiments – USA Series, (7 x 10) (1002—006)
    - Science in Art Lecture, (12 x 14) (1002—007)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 1, (12 x 14) (1002—008)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 2, (12 x 14) (1002—009)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 3, (12 x 14) (1002—010)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 4, (12 x 14) (1002—011)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 5, (12 x 14) (1002—012)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 6, (12 x 14) (1002—013)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 7, (12 x 14) (1002—014)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 8, (12 x 14) (1002—015)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 9, (12 x 14) (1002—016)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 10, (12 x 14) (1002—017)
    - Science in Art Lecture no. 11, (12 x 14) (1002—018)
    - Moorish Architecture Poster, (12.25 x 18.75) (1002—019)
    - Will Carter Poster, (9 x 15.25) (1002—020)
    - Vishniac Poster, (9.25 x 16) (1002—021)
    - Design in Brazil Poster, (10 x 19) (1002—022)
    - Seasons Greetings 1961, (4.75 x 19) (1002—023)
    - Seasons Greetings 1962, (10.5 x 12) (1002—024)
    - Seasons Greetings 1963, (9 x 14.5) (1002—025)
    - Seasons Greetings 1964, (3.5 x 13) (1002—026)
    - Seasons Greetings 1965, (7 x 11.5) (1002—027)
    - Seasons Greetings 1966, (4 x 13.5) (1002—028)
    - Alphabet Design – caps only (1002—029)
    - Alphabet Design (Oberon) – sketches (1002—030)
    - Type Experiments, (8.25 x 10.75) (1002—031)
    - Type Talks – cover, (6.5 x 9.5) (1002—032)
    - Design pattern, (7 x 10) (1002—033)
    - Self Promo piece, (9 x 20) (1002—034)
    - PGAC Trademark, (8.5 x 10.5) (1002—035)
    - NAC Trademark, (7 x 8.5) (1002—036)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 9) (1002—037)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 9) (1002—038)
    - Book Jacket Design, (5.5 x 8.5) (1002—039)
    - Book Jacket Design, (5.5 x 8.5) (1002—040)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 8.5) (1002—041)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 8.5) (1002—042)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 8.5) (1002—043)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 8.5) (1002—044)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 8.5) (1002—045)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6.25 x 9.25) (1002—046)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6.25 x 9.25) (1002—047)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6 x 9) (1002—048)
    - Book Jacket Design, (6.75 x 10.25) (1002—049)
    - Book Jacket Design, (8.75 x 11) (1002—050)
    - Book Jacket Design, (9 x 12) (1002—051)
    - Book Jacket Design, (9 x 12.25) (1002—052)
    - Faculty Booklet, (8 x 8.25) (1002—053)
    - Poster/Booklet, (17 x 19.5) (1002—054)
    - Pamphlet, (11 x 17) (1002—055)
    - Miniature Prints Brochure, (3.75 x 9) (1002—056)
    - Theater Graphics, (4.5 x 12.5) (1002—057)
    - David Amram Brochure, (3.5 x 8.5) (1002—058)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—059)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—060)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—061)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—062)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—063)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—064)
    - Record Album Design, (12.25 x 12.25) (1002—065)
    - Stationary Design (1002—066)
    - Liber Mobile Brochure, (6.75 x 24) (1002—067)
    - Invitation, (4 x 8) (1002—068)
    - Brochure /Poster, (12 x 31) (1002—069)
    - Brochure, (6 x 31) (1002—070)
    - Poster, (12.5 x 19) (1002—071)
    - Letter A – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—072)
    - Letter B – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—073)
    - Letter C – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—074)
    - Letter D – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—075)
    - Letter E – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—076)
    - Letter G – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—077)
    - Letter K – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—078)
    - Letter M – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—079)
    - Letter N – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—080)
    - Letter P – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—081)
    - Letter P – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—082)
    - Letter Q – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—083)
    - Letter Q – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—084)
    - Letter T – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—085)
    - Letter T – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—086)
    - Letter S – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—087)
    - Letter X – matted, (13 x 13) (1002—088)
    - Letter B – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—089)
    - Letter D – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—090)
    - Letter e – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—091)
    - Letter E – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—092)
    - Letter G – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—093)
    - Letter H – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—094)
    - Letter i – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—095)
    - Letter i – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—096)
    - Letter j – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—097)
    - Letter j – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—098)
    - Letter j – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—099)
    - Letter L – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—100)
    - Letter L – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—101)
    - Letter L – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—102)
    - Letter M – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—103)
    - Letter p – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—104)
    - Letter r – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—105)
    - Letter T – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—106)
    - Letter w – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—107)
    - Letter Y – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—108)
    - Letter Y – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—109)
    - Letter Z – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—110)
    - Letter Z – work proofs, loose, (13 x 13) (1002—111)
  - 1003: Teaching Activity
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Antigone, (40 x 80) (1003—001)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Enemies, (40 x 80) (1003—002)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Enemy of the People, (40 x 80) (1003—003)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Playboy of the Western World, (40 x 80) (1003—004)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Road to the Deep North, (40 x 80) (1003—005)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Plow and the Stars, (40 x 80) (1003—006)
    - Title sheet, (16 x 32) (1003—007)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Danton's Death, (16 x 32) (1003—008)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Country Wife, (16 x 32) (1003—009)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Condemned of Altona, (16 x 32) (1003—010)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Caucasian Chalk Circle, (16 x 32) (1003—011)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Little Foxes, (16 x 32) (1003—012)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Saint Joan, (16 x 32) (1003—013)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — 12th Night, (16 x 32) (1003—014)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Narrow Road to the Deep North, (16 x 32) (1003—015)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Antigone, (16 x 32) (1003—016)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — The Miser, (16 x 32) (1003—017)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — In the Matter of J.R. Oppenheimer, (16 x 32) (1003—018)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — A Cry of Players, (16 x 32) (1003—019)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — King Lear, (16 x 32) (1003—020)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Cyrano, (16 x 32) (1003—021)
    - Student poster for Lincoln Center project — Tiger at the Gates, (16 x 32) (1003—022)
    - Class project — 12 Alphabet Designs, (18 x 24) (1003—023)
    - Selections from The Diary of a Madman by Samuel Alexander, (19 x 14.5) (1003—024 A)
    - Master Thesis towards an MFA degree — Proba – 13 experimental broad sides numbered B1–B13, (19 x 14.5) (1003—024 B)
    - Class project — Typografie am Pratt Institute, (6.75 x 9.5) (1003—025)
    - Class project — Nursery Rhymes, 30 page booklet, (7 x 6.75) (1003—026)
    - Class project — GAD 346/348, (28 11 x 14 broadsides) (1003—027)
    - Student design — Playbill cover – Condemned of Altona, (8 x 11) (1003—028)
    - Student design — Playbill cover – Caucasian Chalk Circle, (8 x 11) (1003—029)
    - Student design — Playbill cover – The Little Foxes, (8 x 11) (1003—030)
    - Student design — Playbill cover – St. Joan, (8 x 11) (1003—031)
    - Student design — Playbill cover – The East Wind, (8 x 11) (1003—032)
    - Lincoln Center Journal, (8 x 11) (1003—033)
    - Student book — The Trauma of Willie, (6 x 8.25) (1003—034)
    - Essays on Asian Music and Theater, 1971-1972; (5 x 14.5) (1003—035)
    - Essays on Asian Music and Theater, 1973-1974; (7 x 6.75) (1003—036)
    - Class Project — A to Z – alphabet design, 8.25 x 8.25 (1003—037)
    - Student Project — Alphabet in Clay – sewn poster, (31 x 71) (1003—038)
    - Class Project — 15 Student Alphabets, (11 x 14) (1003—039)
    - 54 Student Collages, 1991-1993; (various sizes) (1003—040)
    - Student book — Bones for the Archaeologist, (8 x 8.5) (1003—041)
    - Student book — Transformations – collage foldout, (8.5 x 11) (1003—042)
    - Student book — Typographic exp. around the alphabet, (8 x 10.25) (1003—043)
    - Student book — Stories around the letter B, (8.25 x (8.75) (1003—044)
    - Student book — Variations of the letter M, (8.5 x 10.75) (1003—045)
    - Student book — Exploring the letter U, (8.5 x 10.5) (1003—046)
    - Class project — Alphabetica I, 1999; (5.5 x 8.25) (1003—047)
    - Class project — Alphabetica II, 2000; (5.5 x 8.25) (1003—048)
    - Class project — Alphabetica III, 2001; (5.5 x 8.25) (1003—049)
    - Class project — Alphabetica IV, 2001; (5.5 x 8.25) (1003—050)
    - Class project — 9/11 and the aftermath, 2002; (7 x 8) (1003—051)
    - 80 Slides of student books (1003—052)
    - Art of the Book classes, (8.5 x 9.5) (1003—053)
    - Typographic Design classes, (8.5 x 9.5) (1003—054)
    - ComD Graphic Design classes, (8.5 x 9.5) (1003—055)
    - Art of the book demo sample — 'Kerf' binding, (11.5 x 8.75) (1003—056)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Box with multiple papers, (9 x 9) (1003—057)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Accordion fold, (8 .25 x 9.25) (1003—058)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Blind embossment technique, (10 x 8) (1003—059)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Material study, ribbons, (7 x 8) (1003—060)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Binding several signatures, (5.75 x 9.25) (1003—061)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Collage print, inlaid label, (5.25 x 7.25) (1003—062)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Simple sewn or stapled book, (5.25 x 7) (1003—063)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Japanese binding, (4.75 x 8) (1003—064)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Perfect binding, (5.5 x 8.5) (1003—065)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Concertina binding, (5 x 8.5) (1003—066)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Diamond Fold, (4.25 x 4.25) (1003—067)
    - Art of the book demo sample — Altered book in a box, (8.5 x 11 x 1.5) (1003—068)
  - 1004: Presentations
    - Delta Serie (housing project), Germany, 1978; (13 x 8.5) (1004—001)
    - JVA Hameln (juvenile prison), Niedersachsen, Germany, 1979; (16 x 9.5) (1004—002)
    - Allianz (insurance company head quarters), Stuttgart, 1981; (11 x 9.75) (1004—003)
    - Justiz Behörde (courthouse), Stuttgart, 1981; (11.5 x 8.25) (1004—004)
    - Altersheim Bietigheim (senior citizen's facility), 1981; (11 x 8) (1004—005)
    - Gymnasium Bissingen (high school), southern Germany, 1982; (14 x 11) (1004—006)
    - Florida Atlantic University, 1984; (10.75 x 8) (1004—007)
    - Hartford Legislature, 1985; (7.75 x 10.5) (1004—008)
    - Howell Cheney School, Connecticut, 1986; (16 x 9.5) (1004—009)
    - Windrad – Fliegerhorst Wunsdorf (German Air Force barracks), 1989; (8.5 x 10.75) (1004—010)
    - University of Connecticut Law Library, Hartford, 1994; (9.25 x 11.75) (1004—011)
    - Windsong, Denver Hospital, 1995; (9.25 x 11.75) (1004—012)
    - Deutsche Schule (German school), London, 1981; (11 x 8.5) (1004—013)
    - Madonna Hall, Pittsfield, 1982; (15 x 9.5) (1004—014)
    - Arts on the Line, Boston, 1985; (9.75 x 11.5) (1004—015)
    - Wolcott Vocational School, 1998; (8.25 x 8.5) (1004—016)
    - Bullard-Haven, Bridgeport, 1999; (16.5 x 10.75) (1004—017)
    - Percent for Arts Project proposal, Castleton State College, Vermont (1004—018)
    - Percent for Arts Project proposal, Shelby Library, Sarasota, Florida (1004—019)
    - Percent for Arts Project proposal, Court Building, Waterbury, Connecticut – documentation of commission (1004—020)
    - Percent for Arts Project proposal, Rhode Island Community College (1004—021)
    - Percent for Arts Project proposal, Seattle Central Library (1004—022)
  - 1005: X-mas Cards
    - X-mas Card no. 1, 1974; (8 x 10) (1005—001)
    - X-mas Card no. 2, 1975; (8 x 10) (1005—002)
    - X-mas Card no. 3, 1976; (8 x 10) (1005—003)
    - X-mas Card no. 4, 1977; (8 x 10) (1005—004)
    - X-mas Card no. 5, 1978; (8 x 10) (1005—005)
    - X-mas Card no. 6, 1979; (8 x 10) (1005—006)
    - X-mas Card no. 7, 1980; (8 x 10) (1005—007)
    - X-mas Card no. 8, 1981; (8 x 10) (1005—008)
    - X-mas Card no. 9, 1982; (5.5 x 6.5) (1005—009)
    - X-mas Card no. 10, 1983; (5.5 x 7) (1005—010)
    - X-mas Card no. 11, 1984; (5.75 x 3.75) (1005—011)
    - X-mas Card no. 12, 1985; (8 x 9) (1005—012)
    - X-mas Card no. 13, 1986; (5.5 x 3.75) (1005—013)
    - X-mas Card no. 14, 1987; (5 x 7) (1005—014)